Guide to the Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Class Records, 1869-1969; Series IX
  - Class of 1906s
    - Sixtieth Reunion Book, 1966 (Box 117, Folder 1237)
  - Class of 1907s
    - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 118, Folder 1238)
    - Fifty Years Out of Yale, 1907s, 1957 (Box 118, Folder 1239)
    - Now and Then 1907-1937 (Box 118, Folder 1240)
    - Resolution on the disposal of class funds, 1966 June 17 (Box 118, Folder 1241)
    - Reunion Memorabilia
      - Buttons (Box 118, Folder 1242)
      - Banner (Box 119)
      - Blazer (Box 120)
      - Blazer and cap (Box 121)
      - Motion picture films
        - Twentieth reunion: three rolls of 16 mm film, 1927 (Box 122)
        - Twentieth and twenty-fifth reunions: one roll of 16 mm film, 1927, 1932 (Box 123)
        - Twenty-fifth and thirtieth reunions: one roll of 16 mm film, 1932, 1937 (Box 123)
        - Fortieth and forty-fifth reunions: one roll of 16 mm film, 1947, 1952 (Box 123)
        - Fiftieth and fifty-fifth reunions: one roll of 16 mm film, 1957, 1962 (Box 123)
  - Class of 1908s
    - Reunion Film
      - Fifteenth reunion: one roll of 16 mm film, 1923 (Box 124)
      - Fortieth reunion: one roll of 16 film, 1948 (Box 124A)
    - Reunion Slides
      - Fortieth and forty-fifth reunion: two boxes of slides, 1948, 1953 (Box 125)
      - Forty-fifth reunion: one envelope, 1953 (Box 126)
      - Fiftieth reunion: two envelopes, 1958 (Box 126)
      - Reunion slides: two envelopes, undated (Box 126)
      - Reunion slides (glass): one envelope, undated (Box 126)
    - Reunion register, 1914-1963 (Box 127, Folder 1243)
    - Forty-fifth reunion register, 1953 (Box 127, Folder 1244)
    - Photographs
      - Class dinner, 1922 February 9 (Box 127, Folder 1245)
      - (Eleventh) reunion portrait, 1919 (Box 127, Folder 1246)
      - (Twentieth) reunion portrait, 1928 (Box 127, Folder 1247)
      - Thirtieth reunion portrait, 1938 (Box 127, Folder 1248)
      - Fortieth reunion portrait, 1948 (Box 127, Folder 1249)
      - Reunion portraits, undated (Box 127, Folder 1250)
  - Class of 1911s
    - Testimonial to the services rendered by Yale men in the two world wars and signatures, 1946 (Box 133)
- Photographs and Memorabilia, circa 1848-1951; Series X
  Series X, PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA, is divided into two sections:
  Photographs
  Memorabilia
  The photographs contain pictures of people and buildings associated with the Sheffield Scientific School. Memorabilia consists of a small leather pouch in which the Trustees kept some of the school's historical papers.
  See also: Series IX, Class records, for more photographs and memorabilia relating to specific classes
  - Photographs
    - Analytical Laboratory, 1847-1960 (Box 128, Folder 1253)
    - Brush, George Jarvis: postcard of a portrait painted in October 1897 by Professor John F. Weir (Box 128, Folder 1254)
    - Chemical laboratory in South Sheffield Hall: photographs and correspondence, circa 1900, 1940 (Box 128, Folder 1255)
    - Chittenden, Russell Henry: photo portrait (Box 133)
    - Freshman Row, circa 1898 (Box 128, Folder 1256)
    - Neits, Levi Clinton, general fund donor: postcard portrait (Box 128, Folder 1257)
    - North Sheffield Hall (Box 128, Folder 1258)
    - South Sheffield Ball (Box 128, Folder 1259)
  - Memorabilia
    - Small red leather case belonging to the Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School (Box 128, Folder 1260)
- Class registers, lists, and grade books, 1848-1951; Series XI
  Restricted 75 years from date of creation.
  Series XI contains class registers, lists, and grade books from 1848-1853 and 1874-1951.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1848-1853 (Box 134)
  - 1874-1877 (Box 135)
  - 1878-1884 (Box 136)
  - 1883-1890 (Box 137)
  - 1886-1893 (Box 138)
  - 1891 (Box 139)
  - 1892 (Box 140)
  - 1893 (Box 141)
  - 1894 (Box 142–143)
  - 1894-1909 (Box 144)
  - 1895 (Box 145)
  - 1896 (Box 146–147)
  - 1897 (Box 148)
  - 1898 (Box 149)
  - 1900 (Box 150)
  - 1901 (Box 151)
  - 1902 (Box 152)
  - 1903 (Box 153)
  - 1904 (Box 154)
  - 1905 (Box 155)
  - 1906 (Box 156)
  - 1910 (Box 157)
  - 1918 (Box 158)
  - 1919-1931 (Box 159)
  - 1932-1945 (Box 160)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2021
  - 1945-1950 (Box 161)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - 1951 (Box 162)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2027
- Additions
  - Scrapbooks (Box 130)
  - Records of the Director (Box 131–132)
- Records of the registrar, 1938, 1945-1969; Accession 2000-A-005
  - Accounts Treasurers office chart of accounts, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appropriation ledger Accounts, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounts (unlabeled folder), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accounts, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget Accounts (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Accounts: requisitions, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accounts: requisitions, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Accounts: requisitions, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Accounts: requisitions (fall), 1958 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Accounts: Secretary's employment blanks (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Accounts: Budget undergraduate activity office, 1945-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Accounts: Budget, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Accounts: Budget, 1968- 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Accounts: Budget, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Accounts: Budget undergraduate school, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Accounts: suggested basic calendar (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Calendar: Undergraduate calendar, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Calendar: Undergraduate calendar, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Calendar:, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Calendar:, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - University Calendar:, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Calendar:, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Calendar:, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Calendar:, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - University Calendar:, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Class hours- departmental distribution, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Class rooms: room assignments (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Class rooms: special requests, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Class rooms: special events, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Summer programs, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Aurelian and Torch (use of rooms for seminars) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Book containing plans for halls (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Courses of study costs, 1945-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Courses of study- General correspondence, 1945-1959 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Courses of study form letters, 1945-1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Courses of study printing schedules number of copies ordered, 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Examination schedules: examination, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Examination schedules:, 1953-1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Examination schedules:, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Examination schedules:, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Examination schedules:, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Examination schedules: changes in exam schedule, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Examination schedules:, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Examination schedules:, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Examination schedules:, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Examination schedules:, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Faculty offices, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Dean Havemeyer office space committee (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Audio visual center (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Central records office (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Class dates (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Committee on allocations, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Education in colleges (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Evaluation of faculty by students (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Griffith, Mrs. Chas. F. re Chateau de la Napoule (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - President A. Whitney Griswold (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Historical documents: W WII memorial, Hadley inauguration, Virginia bill of rights (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Memorandums, 1954-1966 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Offices, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Procession marshal Mr. Havemeyer, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Provost, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Purchasing procedure and stock list, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Registration (methods of) other colleges, 1943 -1950 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Remittance slips, 1944- 1958 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Service bureau, 1948, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Three hour exams, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Notices-Yale News, etc.:, 1945- 1964 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Notices-Yale News, etc.: WYBC, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Notices-Yale News, etc.: Yale dames, 1947-1952 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Notices-Yale News, etc.: Post- War plans Yale studies, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Notices-Yale News, etc.: Misc., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - White Pamphlet:, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - White Pamphlet:, 1963- 1964 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - White Pamphlet:, 1964- 1965 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - White Pamphlet: white pamphlet changes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - White Pamphlet:, 1965- 1966 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - White Pamphlet changes:, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - White Pamphlet: costs, number of copies, etc. (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - White Pamphlet: form letters, 1945-1956 (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Dean's correspondence, 1906-1940; Accession 2002-A-010 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook documenting the Sheffield Scientific School's YMCA, 1901-1921; Accession 2003-A-109
  - Scrapbook documenting the Sheffield Scientific School's YMCA, 1901-1921 (Box 1)
- Letters from alumni of the Industrial Administration Program, 1953; Accession 2004-A-106
  - Letters from alumni of the Industrial Administration Program, 1953 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia of Robert E. Burton, Class of 1957, concerning the Sheffield Scientific School, circa 1915-1955; Accession 2004-A-190 (Box 1)
- Board of Trustees records, 1909-1970; Accession 2012-A-077
  - Charter, by-laws, memoranda and correspondence, 1909-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Scrapbook of student and faculty photographs, 1910-1930; Accession 2018-A-0067
  Open for research.
  - Scrapbook, 1910-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)